( CLANGING )
( DRAWER CLOSES )
( INAUDIBLE )
( CELL PHONE RINGING )
BEN ON PHONE : Michelle , please don 't hang up .
Just talk to me , okay ? I can 't believe you just left .
Michelle .
Come back .
Please say something .
Michelle , talk to me .
Look , we had an argument . Couples fight .
That is no reason to just leave everything behind .
Running away isn 't gonna help it any . Michelle , please ...
( DIALTONE )
NEWSCASTER : More details on that .
Elsewhere today , power has still not been restored
to many cities on the southern seaboard
in the wake of this afternoon 's widespread blackout .
While there had been some inclement weather in the region ,
the problem seems linked to what authorities are calling
a catastrophic power surge that has crippled traffic in the area .
- ( LOUD CRASH ) - ( GRUNTS )
- ( TIRES SCREECHING ) - ( SCREAMS )
- ( GLASS SHATTERING ) - ( GASPING )
( GROANS )
( HORN HONKING )
( INHALES DEEPLY )
( SNIFFS )
( SIGHS )
( GASPING )
( CHAINS RATTLING )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( GRUNTING )
( GROANING )
( SOBS ) No .
( CHAIN JANGLING )
No ! ( SOBBING )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
Damn .
( CLATTERS )
( GRUNTS )
( RUMBLING )
( FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING )
( PANTING )
( GASPS )
( DOOR CREAKING )
Okay . Okay , please .
Please .
Please don 't hurt me .
( BREATHING HEAVILY ) Please .
Just let me go , okay ? I won 't tell anybody .
I promise , okay ? Please just let me go . Please .
MAN : You need fluids . You were in shock .
What are you going to do to me ?
I 'm going to keep you alive .
Work on getting handy with these .
My boyfriend was expecting me .
He 'll send the cops looking .
I 'm sorry .
But no one is looking for you .
( CLANGS )
( GRUNTS )
( GROANS SOFTLY )
( EXHALES )
( SCRAPING )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( SIGHS )
( COUGHING )
( FIRE ALARM BEEPING )
( RAPID FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING )
( DOOR OPENS )
- ( GASPA ) - ( GRUNTS )
( SCREAMING )
( MAN CLEARS THROAT )
( GASPS )
You 've got some fight in you .
I can respect that .
But don 't even think about trying that again .
You 're lucky to be here at all .
And my generosity only extends so far .
Eggs .
Toradol to help with your pain .
Please .
Please , just let me go . Please .
There is nowhere to go , Michelle .
I looked through your wallet .
Given as how I saved your life , I think that 's acceptable .
You 're lucky to be here at all .
What do you mean ?
I found you , and I saved your life by bringing you here .
I don 't understand . I ...
( SIGHING )
There 's been an attack .
What ?
An attack . A big one .
I 'm not sure yet if it 's chemical or nuclear ,
but down here , we 're safe .
- And where are we exactly ? - Underneath my farmhouse .
Forty miles outside of Lake Charles .
I was driving north of here .
You were in an accident .
You were turned over on the side of the road .
I was driving by and I saw ...
I saved your life , Michelle .
I couldn 't just leave you there .
( SOFTLY ) Okay .
Well ,
thank you so much
for saving my life .
I guess I should go to a hospital now .
You can 't leave .
An attack means fallout .
Which contaminates the air above ground .
( STUTTERS ) That 's how it works .
How long do we have to wait until it 's safe ?
Depends on the proximity of the closest blast .
One year , maybe two .
( HOWARD SIGHS )
And that 's if we 're talking about weapons that we know of .
Russians are developing some nasty stuff .
And if the Martians finally figured out a way to get here ,
their weapons will make the Russkies ' look like sticks and stones .
Luckily ,
I 've prepared for this .
( SOFTLY ) Right .
Well , I 'll need to use your phone then
to call my family and tell them that I 'm safe here
and make sure they 're okay .
Michelle , they 're not okay .
( HOWARD SIGHS )
How do you know that ?
Everyone outside of here is dead .
But what about you ? Don 't you have a family ?
( OBJECTS CLATTERING )
Who 's that ?
Excuse me .
HOWARD : ( SHOUTS ) What did you do ?
( LOUD THUDDING )
( INDISTINCT SHOUTING )
( GASPS )
You know what , Michelle ? I 'm gonna tell you what I told him .
You need to eat , you need to sleep ,
and you need to start showing me a little bit of appreciation .
My name is Howard , by the way .
( DOOR CREAKING )
( DOOR LOCKS )
( VEHICLE ENGINE STARTS )
( VEHICLE DRIVES AWAY )
( MUSIC PLAYING IN DISTANCE )
- ( CLATTERS ) - ( GASPS )
Oh , God ! Oh , shit .
I 'm sorry . ( CHUCKLES )
( GROANS SOFTLY )
I 'm sorry about that .
Uh , I didn 't mean to scare you .
Are you , um ...
Here . You hungry ?
So , how are you doing ? You okay ?
- What is this ? - It 's a bunker .
Your room 's a little bit of a fixer-upper , but at least you got a door .
A scary door , but you still got a door .
How long have you been down here ?
Couple of days , I think .
You know , it 's actually kind of hard to tell
with no windows or sunlight or anything . ( CHUCKLES )
( WHISPERS ) I mean , how do we get out of here ?
Oh , he didn 't tell you ?
About ...
Getting out of here is the last thing you want to do .
Because the air up there ,
it 's contaminated .
HOWARD : I see you 've met Emmett .
What happened to him ?
He did that to himself .
And his stumbling around isn 't helping anything .
What you heard earlier ,
was him knocking over a shelf with a whole week 's worth of food ,
which he 's sorry for , correct ?
Totally .
Let 's go . Bathroom time .
( MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING )
HOWARD : This is the common area .
Good for R R.
As you can see , I 've planned for a long stay .
The aquaponics system cleans the air and keeps it fresh .
This is the living room . Help yourself to any reading .
If you like to watch films , I have some on DVD and VHS cassette .
Just make sure you put them back in their sleeve when they 're done .
The kitchen 's fully functional .
Has an electric stove , refrigerator , freezer , silverware .
And that table 's a family heirloom ,
which means watch your glasses .
Always use coasters and placemats .
Keep your hands to yourself !
Understand ?
No touching .
Take a seat .
This way .
This is my private space .
Off-limits , unless I give express permission .
Go ahead .
- I don 't need to . - You will , though .
And I 've got to pace these things out , so please .
I need privacy .
You 're welcome to close the curtain .
I can 't with you standing there .
And I can 't trust you not to burn this place down .
This is for my own safety .
I 'm not some pervert ! Just go .
( SIGHING )
HOWARD : Don 't flush unless you 've gone !
We can 't afford wasted flushes .
Take a seat . Are you hungry ?
- Those are Megan 's . - ( VESSELS CLANG )
She never went anywhere without two or three of those things .
Who 's Megan ?
Megan 's not with us anymore .
( FAINT WHIRRING )
Don 't worry . Just the generator .
Maybe it 's a car outside .
( SCOFFS )
That 's not possible .
I heard one earlier . Above my room .
If you had heard a car , the driver would be long dead by now .
Well , shouldn 't we at least try
to call the police or someone to find out what actually happened ?
There 's no one left to call .
See that ? Nothing 's coming through .
( HOWARD EXHALES DEEPLY )
You think I sound crazy .
I mean , it 's amazing . You people ...
You wear helmets when you ride your bikes .
You have seat belts in your cars .
You have alarm systems to protect your homes .
But what do you do when those alarms go off ?
" Crazy " is building your ark after the flood has already come !
I think maybe it 's time you met Frank and Mildred .
( KEYS JANGLING )
Closest I could get to an airlock .
- ( GASPING ) - See ?
What happened to them ?
They weren 't as lucky as you .
It 's the air , Michelle .
That 's what happens when you get exposed .
( CELL PHONE RINGING )
( TIRES SQUEALING )
( CRASHING )
I keep this door sealed at all times .
No one comes in or out .
EMMETT : Met Frank and Mildred , huh ?
It 's funny , right ?
The whole world ends
and the thing he 's most upset about is a pair of dead pigs ?
You in need of some reading material ?
I took all the quizzes . Sorry .
But I did learn how to do a French braid , so ,
you know , if you want me to do that for you , just let me know .
What do you know about him ?
He was in the Navy , I know that .
I guess he did , uh , some stuff with satellites .
What kind of stuff ?
Satellite stuff .
Well , what brought him out here ?
I 'm not sure .
He bought this property a while back .
But I never paid much attention
till he hired me to help him get this place set up .
The work was entertaining , though , that 's for sure . ( CHUCKLES )
You know , Howard 's like a black belt in conspiracy theory .
Plus , you know , how often do you get hired to help build
a doomsday bunker ?
So , he didn 't
kidnap you ?
( SCOFFS ) No !
What about your arm ? Weren 't you trying to escape ?
I was trying to get in .
I watched Howard build this place , piece by piece , for years .
He was always talking about ,
you know , possible attacks from
Al Qaeda , Russia , South Korea .
You mean North Korea .
( STUTTERS ) ls that the crazy one ?
So , yeah , that one .
And , uh , you know , poured all his money into this place .
Took to it like his life depended on it .
Which , you know ,
that stays with you .
So ...
( GRUNTS SOFTLY )
He told you all this
while you 're building his bomb shelter .
And now he says that
the air is contaminated and everybody 's dead .
Yeah , I know what you 're getting at , but there 's more to it .
Howard abducted me .
He drove me off the road and he dragged me here .
So , whatever he 's telling you about the air , some big attack ,
the purpose of this shelter , is a lie .
No . No way .
The attack , I saw it myself .
What do you mean ?
I was on my way home from work .
And it looked like a flash .
Bright red .
Like an explosion , from way far off .
It wasn 't like fireworks .
Naw , this was more like something you 'd read about in the Bible .
So , what , you saw , what , a flash of light ? Lightning ?
A fire that flared up ?
I 'm not explaining it right .
This wasn 't like anything I 'd ever seen .
And so , my first thought was to come here .
And when I got here , Howard was closing the door .
And I could see it , right there on his face ,
he knew something was happening .
Something bad .
And so , I fought my way in .
I heard a car .
Right here . Above us .
You heard someone ?
Right above us .
That isn 't possible .
- The air is ... - What , contaminated ?
- How do you know that ? - Because I told him .
Dinner 's ready .
I see you two are getting along .
Hmm .
How 's that sauce ?
It 's fine .
As cooks go , I 'm okay .
Not great , but okay .
Megan was a good cook .
You 'll learn to love cooking .
Mmm ...
EMMETT : Mmm .
It 's delicious .
That 's the best sauce I 've ever tasted .
Are you being funny ?
No , I mean ,
considering the alternative , which is , you know ,
getting burnt up in a chemical attack , or nuclear ,
I 'd say being alive and down here would
make a fried turd taste pretty good , so ...
Best damn sauce I ever had .
That 's not a bad point .
And , please , watch your language at table .
Right ?
You know what I haven 't been able to get out of my head , for some reason ?
Ever since I got down here .
Tattoos .
Always wanted one .
But I never got any . 'Cause everybody always said ,
" No , no , Emmett , you 'll never get a decent job if you do that . "
Whatever .
Like that matters now , right ?
Tell you what , if I had known this was coming ,
I would 've gotten , like , 50 of them . I swear , man .
I would look like a circus freak , or something .
I 'd just be covered head to toe .
Tattoos all over my ... You know , everywhere . Face ?
Sure . Right there . Across my forehead .
Just my name . " Emmett . "
Or , you know ,
- " Thug Life . " - ( CHUCKLES )
" YOLO " .
I don 't even know what that means ,
but , you know , I hear people saying it all the time ,
so , it must be cool . ( CHUCKLES )
Hey , what about you , Howard ?
Anything you wish you 'd done ?
In all honesty , no .
No ?
No crazy nights in Vegas ?
Maybe , uh , take a pilgrimage to Waco ?
Everything I wanted to do , I did .
I focused on being prepared .
And I was .
And here we are .
EMMETT : Oh , my goodness .
Is that Monopoly ?
There we go !
Yeah , that 's how we kill the time .
What would you say , Howard , we 're gonna be down here ,
what , like , a year ? Two ? Maybe ?
I bet you if we started a game right now ,
we might even get halfway finished by the time ...
Stop talking !
( BREATHES DEEPLY )
You don 't need to make jokes about how long we 're going to be down here
when nobody knows how long that 's going to be .
Your humor is not funny .
I don 't appreciate it while I 'm trying to eat ,
and neither does Michelle .
Now , please shut up and let us eat in peace .
Hmm .
Emmett ?
Would you pass me a napkin ?
Thank you .
I know what you 're saying . I never could finish Monopoly .
That game really does take forever , right ?
For me , though , it was , um ...
Chutes and Ladders ,
uh ...
Sorry ! '
and Trouble .
You know , the thing with the dice and the thing that you pressed ,
- what was that called ? - The ...
BOTH : Pop-O-Matic bubble ! Yeah .
Did you ever play that , um ... What was that , Operation ?
- Loved Operation ! - I 'm telling you , man ,
I couldn 't play that game .
- It terrified me . - Why ...
That noise that thing would make when you hit that edge . I mean ...
- Good Lord ! - ( CHUCKLING ) It was pretty scary .
Could you hand me the salt ?
Please ?
Ah , shoot ! I 'm sorry .
I 'm gonna need the pepper also .
What exactly do you think you 're doing ?
I 'm asking for pepper .
Like hell you were ! What was that ?
I don 't know what you 're talking about , Howard .
Are you trying to insult me ?
Here , in the shelter that I built that 's keeping you alive ?
You don 't think I see what you just did ?
Is that how you thank me for saving your life ?
- Howard , calm down . - Shut up !
Shut up and stay in your seat !
IS it ?
Now , let me tell you ,
I know what a traitor looks like .
Understand ?
I have shown you nothing , but generosity and hospitality .
I want you to apologize .
To tell me you 're going to behave .
I will .
You will what ?
I 'll behave .
And I 'm so sorry .
HOWARD : Sit .
( HOWARD SIGHING )
Ah ...
Have to stay hydrated .
Hmm .
That 's easy to forget down here .
What 's wrong ?
( SOFTLY ) Nothing .
Where are my keys ?
( RUMBLING )
( SCREAMS )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
- Michelle ! - ( GRUNTS )
( GROANS )
( PANTING )
Michelle ! Stop !
Give me those keys !
MICHELLE : Come on . HOWARD : No ! Don 't !
( MICHELLE PANTING )
Stop !
No ! No , don 't ! Don 't !
Don 't open that door !
( PANTING )
There 's a car !
- There 's a car ! I see a car ! - HOWARD : No !
Here ! Here ! Here !
HOWARD : Michelle , listen to me , don 't do this !
- ( THUD ) - ( GASPS )
Oh , God ! Thank God !
- There 's a woman . - WOMAN : Open the door !
( STUTTERING ) It 's okay . I just want to come inside .
She looks hurt . She wants me to let her in .
Do not let her in !
- Look at her face , Michelle ! - No !
No , no , no !
No !
Oh , my God , I 'm fine . I really am fine .
- No , please , I 'm okay . - There 's ...
It really only ... It only touched me a little . A little !
So , could you open the door ? Open it !
- She 's begging me . - You can 't help her !
No one can !
Let me in . I 'll be okay .
I 'll be okay . It really hardly touched me at all .
- Open the door ! - HOWARD : Don 't listen to her !
God ! Open the door , you bitch !
Let me in !
Let me in ! Let me in !
You !
You ! You ! You !
( POUNDING ON DOOR )
( WHIMPERS )
( GRUNTS )
( KEYS JANGLING )
( DOOR OPENING )
( GRUNTS )
I know it 's hard ,
realizing they 're all gone .
The ones you love .
I have something to confess to you .
( GULPS )
I crashed into your car .
Your accident
was my fault .
When I found out about the incoming attack ,
I got frantic .
I knew I needed to get back here as soon as possible ,
so I was driving like a maniac .
( SIGHS )
I tried to pass you ,
and
I 'm the reason you went off the road .
I mean , I know I seem like a sensible guy ,
but at the time , I wasn 't myself .
It was an accident , but it was my fault .
I was afraid to tell you ,
and ,
I 'm sorry .
Um ...
You should shower .
Even the smallest amount of air
that came through the hinges could be toxic .
These were Megan 's .
If you want .
I recognized that woman 's car .
Her name was Leslie , I think .
You knew her ?
She was a neighbor .
Emmett wasn 't the only one who knew about this place .
If any others somehow survived , they could be coming here , too .
( GRUNTS SOFTLY )
As of Friday , kindness and generosity are antiquated customs .
I 'm going to need some stitches .
What ? You want me to ...
This is your doing , isn 't it ?
I mean , I don 't think I 'm really qualified .
I 'll walk you through it .
Here .
Have a drink .
What is it ?
Technically , it 's vodka .
( SLURPING )
Ah ! It 's safe . I distilled it myself .
( SLURPS AND COUGHS )
I just said I distilled it ,
I didn 't say anything about it actually tasting good .
- Yeah , that 's awful . - You want it on the rocks ?
Little trick I taught myself as a young man
stationed on a ship with way too much free time .
Every now and again , if the C.O. was working us too hard ,
we 'd freeze and snap the knob off
the bathroom door while he was still inside .
It usually took him an hour or two to get out .
- I 'm good . - Suit yourself . Cheers .
Ah ...
This is clean .
All you need to do is stitch .
( BREATHING DEEPLY )
( WINCES )
( HOWARD GASPS )
You 're doing fine .
HOWARD : Some stuff I grabbed from your car .
I didn 't have time to bring in the booze . Sadly .
What is all that ?
I wanted to design clothes .
No wonder you were so good with the stitches .
Megan wanted to be an artist .
She was your daughter ?
Yes .
She was smart .
Loved to read . The magazines were just for fun .
She inhaled books . Anything with Paris .
She liked their movies , their culture , you know .
We used to have this little joke .
Every once in a while I 'd ask her ,
" What do you want to be when you grow up ? "
You know what she 'd say ?
" French . " ( CHUCKLES )
Anyway , her mother turned her against me .
Took her off to Chicago .
People are strange creatures .
You can 't always convince them that safety is in their own best interest .
You don 't know they 're gone .
Anyway , at least I tried to help them .
- EMMETT : Hey . - ( KNOCKING ON WALL )
There was nothing you could 've done for that woman .
Even if you let her in , she still would 've died .
You asked earlier about regrets ?
Yeah , I 've got some of those .
Welcome to the club .
( SCOFFS )
I mean , I lived my life in a 40-mile radius .
And that was by design . I made sure that happened .
I was so fast in high school ,
I even managed to outrun my bad grades .
I was All-State track three years in a row .
( SNIFFLES AND CLICKS TONGUE )
Caught a full ride to Louisiana Tech , up there in Ruston .
( CHUCKLES )
I remember I spent the last two weeks of that summer
showing off the bus ticket they sent me to anybody who 'd take a look at it .
And then came the night before I was supposed to leave .
And I just got so worried
about how bad I was gonna do up there
with all those smart kids .
So , I went out of my way
to get just piss-wasted so bad
that I knew there was no chance I was waking up in the morning .
So , I missed the bus .
And I didn 't buy a ticket for the next one .
Or the one after that .
Well , if you 'd gone , you might be dead now .
( CHUCKLING ) Yeah , lucky me , right ?
Lucky us .
( STUTTERS ) A few years ago ,
I was at a hardware store .
And there was this little girl with her dad .
And he was in a hurry , and she wasn 't keeping up .
So , he kept
yanking on her arm .
But really hard , you know ?
Too hard .
I know that feeling .
When my dad got that way ,
my brother Colin was always there to take the worst of it
for me .
And I thought , seeing this little girl ,
I thought maybe I could do that
for her .
But I just kept watching .
And they 're about to leave , and I 've done nothing .
And she slips .
And it throws him off-balance , and he hits her .
And I wanted so badly to do something
to help her , but ...
I did what I always do when things get hard .
I just panicked and ran .
( SCOFFS )
( SNIFFLES )
Look , we 're here .
We 're alive .
And that means something .
It 's gotta .
( SIGHS )
( UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING )
( MAN ULULATING ON TV )
( MAN SCREAMING ON TV )
- You 've got to be kidding me . - What ?
We 're missing pieces here .
Look at this poor cat . He 's been deformed . He 's got one eye .
He 's about to go snorkeling and everything , too .
What are you doing ?
Ooh !
Cornering the market on post-apocalyptic fashion , huh ?
Mmm-hmm .
You need more axes and chain saws .
For what ? She has a shotgun .
Yeah . But what if up there it 's like ...
What ? Lumberjacks ?
Zombies .
Though even Howard doesn 't think that one 's plausible .
But you should hear his theory about mutant space worms .
( CHUCKLES SOFTLY )
( RUMBLING )
What is that ? Howard !
Stay calm . We 're okay .
( RUMBLING AND CLANGING )
- What was that ? - Quiet .
That sounds like helicopters .
HOWARD : Could be military .
But not ours .
- EMMETT : How can you tell ? - Fourteen years in the Navy .
What 's happening up there ?
My guess ?
Those flashes that kicked this all off ?
That was phase one .
Take out your opponent 's population centers
with big hits , all at once , fast .
And then for round two ,
ground sweeps .
A satellite log showed an increase in coded traffic recently .
Possibly extraterrestrial signals .
I bet what we just heard were airborne patrols
sent to hunt down the remaining signs of life .
Like us .
- ( SOFT WHIRRING ) - ( ALARM BUZZING )
Okay . Oh , boy .
That 's bad .
( GRUNTS )
And that 's worse .
What 's up there ?
Air filtration system .
I can 't ... ( GRUNTS )
Something blocking the hatch .
If we can 't get it back on , we 're gonna run out of breathable air fast .
( HOWARD GRUNTS )
You 're the only one small enough to reach it .
Reach what ?
The filtration system . Through there , the main duct .
Someone needs to get in there and restart it .
Give me a hand .
Let me go . She 's not gonna know her way around the unit .
You won 't fit . Plus your arm . She 'll be fine .
Now , to restart the unit , you just swing the handle off ,
then on , off , then on .
That should do it .
And neither of us will be able to go in and help you if you get stuck .
Don 't get stuck .
( GRUNTING SOFTLY )
HOWARD : Michelle !
Everything okay up there ?
It looks like a dead end .
HOWARD : That 's the incline .
Climb up that and you 're almost there .
Ah , this sucks .
( GRUNTING )
( WHIRRING )
( SIGHING )
EMMETT : What 's wrong ?
( WHISPERS ) Howard .
He lied , he lied about Megan .
What do you mean ?
I think he did something horrible to her .
No , his family moved to Chicago years ago .
What 's this ?
Is that blood ?
Here , come with me .
Wait , that ... That 's not Megan .
What do you mean ?
Yeah . Her name is Brittany . I remember her .
She went to high school with my little sister .
She ...
She went missing . Two years back .
It was on the news and everything .
Most people just thought she skipped town .
There was a message up there .
It said " Help . "
It was scratched on the inside of the window .
And this earring ...
This earring was with it .
Did she ever show back up after she went missing ?
He said to me ... He said to my face , that this was his daughter .
He said this was Megan .
- He took her and he killed her . - ( CLATTERING )
( WHISPERS ) All right , let 's just think .
Maybe we take away his gun .
Tie him up , get him to confess to whatever it is he 's done .
Confess to who ? The police ?
Look , like I said , we can 't be the only survivors , right ?
The woman , she was able to get around , right ?
At least a little .
Yeah , until she died .
Directly above us , making choking noises .
Of all the people to save us ...
HOWARD : Now , that was a great example of teamwork .
Very well done . I feel like some music .
( PUNCHING BUTTONS )
Problem solving always puts me in a musical mood .
( CHEERFUL MUSIC PLAYING )
Michelle ,
you should go shower , just in case .
Sure .
( CHEERFUL MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING )
( SHOWER RUNNING )
I think I might have an idea .
" Ten Better Ways to Style My Bangs " ?
No , not the article . This .
I think I can only make one , but it 's a start .
No kidding .
What are you doing up ? I didn 't wake you up yet .
MAN : Well , I 'm fixing your breakfast .
One egg over medium .
Hey , Howard .
What is this ? You re-watching Sixteen Candles ?
Pretty in Pink .
It was one of Megan 's favorite movies . Can I help you with something ?
No .
No , I 'm just grabbing some water .
( CLEARS THROAT )
( MOVIE CONTINUES PLAYING )
Say , um ...
You know , I was just thinking ... ( CLEARS THROAT )
Not that I 'm trying to tell you how to run this place or anything .
I 'm just a little curious .
Michelle ...
Say , how close do you think she got to that air filtration unit ?
You think she touched it ?
Yeah , I 'm pretty sure she touched it .
Well , I know she cleaned up after and everything ,
but I 'm just thinking ,
given that unit filters God knows what through from outside ,
if she tracked anything back in with her , it 'd be pretty concentrated .
And , I mean , it could be all over the shower and the sink
in your bathroom , right now .
Anyway , it 's just a thought .
( MOVIE RESUMES PLAYING )
( SHUTS TV OFF )
EMMETT : Not bad so far , partner .
MICHELLE : If Howard finds this , he 's gonna kill us .
All right , so , we get the gun away from him .
All right . We tie him up , make sure he isn 't going anywhere .
And then one of us just
goes out and looks for help .
( SIGHS )
( TIMER TICKING )
Um ...
First word .
Uh ...
Tiny .
Small . Pygmy - Urn- -
- Little . - Yep ! Mmm-hmm .
All right , uh , second word .
Ooh ! Michelle is a ...
( STAMMERING )
A girl .
( STAMMERING CONTINUES )
A girl . A child . Um ...
( GRUNTS )
A girl .
No , she 's older , see , so she is a ...
" Little Princess " ?
( TIMER RINGING )
Um ... No , it was woman .
Um , Little Women .
Wow . Little woman .
( SIGHS )
( SNORTS )
Next time , try being a little more specific .
Let 's see here .
( TIMER STARTS TICKING )
I 'm always watching .
Always .
Um ...
God .
I go wherever I want .
Uh ...
I mean ... Well , I don 't know .
I know what you 're doing . I see what you 're doing .
Um ...
I know what you 're up to .
( STAMMERING ) Look , Howard , I don 't know what you 're getting at , but ...
I see you when you 're sleeping .
I know what you 're doing , and I 'm always watching .
Always watching ! I 'm always watching !
Santa Claus !
( CHUCKLES )
You 're Santa Claus .
( TIMER RINGING )
Yeah , Michelle , that 's great .
Except it was Emmett 's turn .
Sorry , I just got a little excited .
Yeah , well , I 'm keeping that point .
Totally . You earned it .
( TAPPING PEN )
( FOOTSTEPS )
Emmett ?
( SHRIEKS )
Hey .
I need your help with something .
Sure .
You .
On deck .
What is this ?
HOWARD : The barrel .
What 's in it ?
Move it into the bathroom .
HOWARD : This is perchloric acid .
Do either of you know what that is ?
It 's usually produced as a precursor to ammonium perchlorate ,
a fuel
used for launching naval satellites into orbit .
It 's highly corrosive .
Dissolves most biological material on contact .
With humans , right down to the bone .
Hey , Howard , uh , what are you showing this to us for ?
You think I 'm an idiot ?
EMMETT : Uh ... ( CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY )
Howard , please , you 're gonna have to tell us
what it is that you 're talking about .
I 'm talking about getting rid of some waste .
Tell me what you two were doing with these .
You tell me what you two were planning , right now !
Howard , listen , just take it easy . Take it easy .
Howard , come on , please .
No . I 'm giving you one chance .
EMMETT : Hey .
Howard , just calm down .
One chance to answer with some dignity , or I swear to God ,
you 're going into this barrel while you 're alive to feel it .
It was me .
All right ? Not her . It 's just me .
- No , no , no , we ... - Stay out of this , all right ?
She doesn 't have a clue what you 're talking about .
I wanted your gun .
And so , I was thinking about making a weapon
to get it from you .
I want her to respect me the way that she respects you .
I 'm not saying that I was right , okay ?
And I 'm sorry .
You 're sorry ?
I 'm sorry .
I accept your apology .
( SIGHS )
( INAUDIBLE )
Listen to me . You heard him . You heard him .
He was making a weapon . He was gonna hurt us .
He was gonna hurt you . And it 's okay .
This was the way it was always supposed to be .
You 're safe .
Now it 's just you and me .
It 's okay , you know .
You should go to your room now .
This next part isn 't something you need to see .
Okay .
Go on .
( SNIFFLES )
( SIGHING )
HOWARD : Michelle ?
Hey .
I thought we 'd change things up tonight
and have dessert before dinner .
After all , we can do whatever we want now .
Would you like a cone or a bowl ?
Megan always wanted hers in a bowl .
She said the cones were too messy .
I know that this isn 't the life you 'd prefer ,
that it isn 't easy for you living down here ,
but I want us to be a happy family .
You and me .
The mess is all taken care of .
So , just hang loose and I 'll go get dinner started .
HOWARD : Michelle ?
( DOOR OPENS )
Everything all right ?
Yeah , I was just about to do some reading .
Hmm .
It 's time to set the table .
Supper 's ready -
Yeah .
Okay .
( METALLIC CLANK )
It keeps doing that . ( STUTTERING ) I don 't know why .
Michelle , why is this loose ?
- Get up . - Why ?
- Get off the mattress now ! - ( GROANS )
( BOTH GRUNTING )
Oh , shit !
Michelle !
Stop ! Goddamn it , get back here !
( PANTING )
( GASPING )
HOWARD : You gonna walk out on me ?
After I saved you and kept you safe , this is how you repay me .
No .
This is . ( GRUNTS )
( SCREAMING )
( HOWARD GROANING )
( HOWARD WHEEZING )
( FIRE ALARM BUZZING )
( GROWLING )
( PANTING )
( YELPS )
HOWARD : Michelle !
( GRUNTING )
( SCREAMS )
( HOWARD GROANING LOUDLY )
( GRUNTS )
- Stop ! - ( YELPS )
You don 't know what 's out there .
You can 't run from them !
( GRUNTS )
HOWARD : Stay With me !
Let me go !
( HOWARD SCREAMS )
( MICHELLE COUGHING )
( COUGHING )
( BREATHING DEEPLY )
( HISSING )
( GRUNTING )
( PANTING )
( RIPPING )
( GASPS )
( GRUNTING )
( GRUNTING FRANTICALLY )
( BREATHING SHAKILY )
( WHIMPERING )
( BIRDS SQUAWKING )
( CHUCKLES )
( SIGHS )
( WHIRRING IN DISTANCE )
( MUFFLED EXPLODING )
- ( EXPLODING ) - ( GASPS )
Oh , come on .
( ALARM WAILING )
( PANTING )
( ALARM CONTINUES )
( SHUDDERING )
( RUSTLING )
( THUDDING )
( GRUNTS )
( ALARM CONTINUES WAILING )
( SNARLS )
Keys , keys , Keys -
Come on , damn it !
- ( THUD ON DOOR ) - ( GASPS )
( THUDDING )
( GASPS )
( SQUEAKING )
( PANTING )
Come on . Come on .
( ALIEN CHITTERING )
( CAR ALARM BEEPS )
( GRUNTING )
( PANTING )
( ALIEN CHITTERING )
Help ! I 'm out here ! Help !
( RUMBLING )
( HISSING )
( PANTING )
( SNARLING )
- ( GRUNTING ) - ( CHITTERING )
( WHIMPERING )
( SCREAMS )
Oh , God .
( RUMBLING )
( GRUNTING )
( SNARLS )
( GROWLS )
( EXPLODING )
( SCREAMING )
( SIGHS )
( GLASS CLINKING )
( PANTING )
Oh , fuck .
( ENGINE SPUTTERS )
( ENGINE SPUTTERS AND STARTS )
( TIRES SCREECHING )
( STATIC ON RADIO )
FEMALE BROADCASTER : The military has taken back the southern seaboard .
If you are hearing this and aren 't in a safe zone ,
head north of Baton Rouge .
But if you have any medical training or combat experience ,
we need help .
There are people in Houston .
There are survivors at Mercy Hospital .
Please help .
Repeat . There are people in Houston who need our help .
Come join us .
We 've taken back the southern seaboard .
And we 're winning .
But if you have any medical training or combat experience ,
there are survivors ...
( TIRES SQUEALING )
( RUMBLING )
Subtitles by Tonyka Team PopHD